A Guide to the Preston Family Papers, 1745-1915, Inventory
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
- Series IV: Land Records, 1746-1821, undated
  - Commissioners Certificates 1782-1790. (Drawer-folder 3:12.)
    Folder includes certificates for David Miller on Cripple Creek in Montgomery County; Absalim Stafford on Wolf Creek in Montgomery County; John Taylor on Clinch River in Montgomery County; John Hudwin [Hudson] on Steven's Creek in Montgomery County; Alexander Ewing on Cripple Creek in Montgomery County; Joseph Onee on Kimberlins Fork of Walkers Creek in Montgomery County; John Payton on Pine Run in Montgomery County; Henry Harman on Walkers Creek in Montgomery County; George Kinsor on Reed Creek in Montgomery County; John Convey on Burks Fork in Montgomery County; John Dispane in Montgomery County; William Grisson on Clapboard Creek in Montgomery County; and John Howard on Little River in Montgomery County.
  - Land Records - Receipts 1774-1798, undated - (Drawer-folder 3:13.)
    15 items.
  - Land Records - Miscellaneous 1768-1821, undated - (Drawer-folder 3:14.)
    13 items. Folder includes records for Thomas Lewis, John Loony, William Preston, William Christian, William Thompson, Skidmore Muncy, Jacob Ziegler, George Fielder, David Steel, Thomas Teas, John Preston, David Culberson, Thomas Marten, William Howard, Prestonville Company, William Anderson, Ely McClanchon, J. M. Clanahan, Abraham Savage, Michael Shugart, John Shannon, John Snyder, and [illegible] Greer.
- Series V: Military Records, 1758-1807, undated
  - Muster Roll and Letter Book 1792 (Drawer-folder 3:1.)
    Folder contains company roll and letter book for Captain John Preston's Company, Virginia Volunteer Militia (112 Regt., 19th Brigade).
  - Miscellaneous 1764-1807, undated. (Drawer-folder 3:2.)
    Folder contains certificates of service for Philip Watkins, Henry Thompson, and Benjamin Christian. Also included are reports of regimental returns for the 75th Regt., Va. Militia and a request for wages from John Groessel dated 1791. Also include is a protest of L. Bowyer, Jacob Movis, William F. Styles, and William Bailey to Colonel Andrew Anderson regarding illegal tendering of their military service by Captain Robert McDowell, 32nd Regt., Va. Militia. A hand-drawn battlefield map of the First Battle of Manassas, 21 July 1861, is also included.
- Series VI: Miscellaneous, 1821, undated
  - Miscellaneous 1821, undated. (Drawer-folder 3:1.)
    Folder includes copies of account statements of Randolph Ross and Treasury Department of Virginia regarding ordnance dated 1817. Also included is a newspaper clipping, "Nearly Two Centuries in One Family," regarding Greenfield plantation in Botetourt County, Va.